Nicolás Marguglio

✓ nicolas.marguglio@gmail.com — • azimut

January 20, 2023

about me

I spend most of my professional carrer maintaining and designing high-scalable Linux systems. More recently, I have been learning how are those systems build from the programming side.

admin skills

Tools emacs, git, tcpdump, nmap, docker, ansible

Servers Apache, Nginx, Kubernetes, qemu, dnsmasq, qmail, postfix, dovecot

DB mysql, postgres, elasticsearch, redis, OpenLDAP

OS Gentoo, Red Hat

programming languages

Advanced common lisp, bash

Intermediate golang, sql

Previous Experience erlang, c, javascript, typescript, python, perl, php, glsl, clojure, rust, ocaml, lua

idioms

Spanish Native

English Upper Intermediate

job experience

Email Hosting Software Engineer III — Web.com

2017-2018

- Worked on the conversion of a Qmail based mail platform from Gentoo to Redhat.
- Created rpms/spec files.
- Worked on the development of a replacement for Qmail on the platform with a solution based on Dovecot.
- Implemented a logging solution based on Fluentd, Kafka and Postgres. To identify bad actors and blacklist them accordingly.
- Worked on optimizing current web performance, adding cache layers and investigating new load balance solutions.

Web Hosting Software Engineer II — Web.com

2014-2016

- Continuing to work on customer support escalation.
- Worked on wordpress multinetwork hosting platform, based on nginx and percona cluster (mysql).
- Packaging and maintaining all the software related to the Gentoo based shared hosting platform.
- Maintaing the in-house configuration management tools and related PXE servers and custom kernel build.
- Worked on the development of a nginx based proxy for SSL-termination. Developed in Lua scripts and redis.
- Deployed a Kubernetes cluster for development of internal applications.

Web Hosting Software Engineer I — Web.com

2011-2013

- Troubleshooting customer issues on a Unix shared web hosting platform.
- As the last level of support I was responsable of understanding in depth the issue and fiding the root cause of it.
- Which consisted of coding issues on the cx code, bad configuration on the server side or missing software configurations.

Jr. Linux System Administrator — Sols S.A.

2011

• Network design and deploy of a OpenVPN node and squid proxy. Maintenance and technical support.

education

Professional Penetration Tester Base4 University 2015 Red Hat System Administrator I IT Collage 2014 Systems Engineer UTN - Incomplete 2010-2011

personal projects

Typescript	 app to search through irc logs, stored in postgres reddit image gallery in React
Common Lisp	 several game engines multiple midi sequencers
Gentoo	 portage repository, to build 3rd party software minimal docker images
Bash	 integrate several tools for automatic recon html scrapper to download wallpapers from different sites
Golang	 rss feed generators, from twitch and github api's command line clients to view comments of different sites ip's metadata gatherer, asking different cloud providers ans whois
Erlang	· monitor of public dns records
C	· local system monitor
Latex	· this resume, build and published through Github Actions